Geoffrey BERGERET French Nationality 26 years old

System & DevOps Engineer

« Divide and Rule »

+44 7842 783612 job@gbergeret.com www.gbergeret.org

Profile

By experience, I acquired lots of skills in several business like: *Software*, *System*, *Network* or *DevOps* Engineer. Now my goal is to focus on the DevOps way: "*Develop your infrastructure as code and automate everything to make it smarter*".

Work Experience

DevOps Engineer at Drivetribe - 08/2016 to now

- Infrastructure as Code with terraform and ansible (all in git).
- Move platform to docker infrastructure with Kubernetes as container scheduler.
- Refactoring environments to be easy to run, update and dispose (qa, staging, prod).
- Work around failure points and scalability to be online as much as possible.
- Improve, speed up and stabilise the releasing process.
- Basically being agile and continuously improving the infrastructure...

DevOps Engineer at Onfido - 04/2016 to 07/2016

- Move to infrastructure as Code with terraform and ansible (all in git).
- Move platform to micro-services infrastructure with Kubernetes as container scheduler.
- Work around failure points to be as much as possible always online.

System and DevOps Engineer at Contentment – 10/2015 to 03/2016

- In charge of all System and DevOps part, sizing the infrastructure and support it.
- Migrate and automate the deployment of the existing architecture in AWS with Docker.

Network Engineer (Apprentice) at Orange SA – 09/2012 to 09/2015

- VPN production automation (B2B) by implementing scripts (in Perl).
- Network support (second line) for routing, QoS, LAN on border side.

System Administrator (Part-time) at SHPS SARL - 02/2011 to 01/2014

- In charge of production the servers: security, installation, automation and deployment.
- Improve services and working environment with: LAMP, SVN, OpenVPN, Proxmox...
- Technical support (second line) to solve customer tickets.

Education & Training

2015: Master of Science in Computer and Network Engineering (1st class) at ESIPE

2011-2012: Master of Science in Computer Engineering (1st class) *at* UTBM Stopped to prioritise professional experience with apprenticeship training.

2011: Two years technical degree in Computer Sciences at IUT in Belfort

Languages Skills

French —> Native

English -> Fluent (live in UK for almost 2 years)

German -> Elementary

Technical Skills

DevOps: Linux, Shell (Bash, Zsh), Ansible, Python, Docker

Infrastructure: AWS, terraform, Kubernetes, Proxmox, Firewall (pfsense, ipables)

Networking: Routing (OSPF, BGP), VRRP, OpenVPN, DHCP, DNS **Database**: MERISE, ORM, MySQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB

Web Developpement: PHP, (x)HTML, CSS (less), Laravel, Jekyll (Liquid)

Software Developpement: UML, Java, C/C++, Subversion, Git, CI/CD (Jenkins)

Management Skills

Project Management Independent

Team organisation Facilitate meeting

Conduct training Seminar facilitator

Hobbies

Jogging Travelling Fitness Cooking

Motorcycle Brunch